Dick Russell papers, Inclusive: 1924-2011, undated, Bulk: 1964-2003, undated
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
Dick Russell papers
Inclusive: 1924-2011, undated, Bulk: 1964-2003, undated
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials http://www.baylor.edu/lib/bcpm/
101
Russell, Dick
56 document boxes.
The Dick Russell papers consist of original manuscripts, research materials, and articles collected by Dick Russell, pertaining primarily to the assassination of John F. Kennedy.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Dick Russell was born on August 19, 1947, in Boston, Massachusetts. Upon graduating in 1969 from the University of Kansas with a B.A. in Humanities, he pursued a career as a writer and journalist. He briefly wrote for Sports Illustrated (1969-1970) before joining the staff of the TV Guide in their Hollywood Bureau (1977-1979).
Russell became strongly interested in studying the assassination of President John F. Kennedy; after 17 years of research, Russell published The Man Who Knew Too Much in 1992. The book argued that an anti-Castro group financed the assassination of President Kennedy; the conspirators hoped that by setting up Lee Harvey Oswald, a known supporter of Castro, they could provoke a full-scale war with Cuba. Russell followed this successful book with the publication of On the Trail of the JFK Assassins in 2008.
In addition to his Kennedy assassination writings, Russell also wrote a wide variety of free-lance articles, which appeared in newspapers as diverse as Family Health, Village Voice, The Nation, and Parenting. A large number of these articles dealt with environmental issues, which led to Russell’s involvement as the Contributing Editor of OnEarth (formerly Amicus Journal) from 1986 to 2004. As an active member of both the Society of Environmental Journalists and PEN USADLas well as an avid sport fishermanDLRussell spent three years lobbying for regulations to protect Atlantic striped bass. In recognition of his efforts, Russell received the National Coalition for Marine Conservation’s Golden Swordfish Award (1984) and the Chevron Conservation Award (1988).
Dick Russell supplemented his environmental endeavors and assassination research with a prolific writing career, authoring 13 books, including Black Genius and the American Experience (1998), Eye of the Whale (2001), Striper Wars: An American Fish Story (2005), and Horsemen of the Apocalypse: The Men Who Are Destroying Life on Earth―And What It Means for Our Children (2017). Russell also co-authored Don’t Start the Revolution Without Me (2008) with Jesse Ventura. He appeared as a guest on national television and radio programs, including NBC Nightly News and Good Morning America, and has guest lectured at numerous institutions, including Harvard, the National Arts Club, and the University of California.
Dick Russell is married and has one child. Though he has traveled widely in Europe, Africa, North America, and Asia, he currently resides in Los Angeles and Boston.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of manuscripts, research materials, and articles collected by Dick Russell, most of which pertain to the assassination of John F. Kennedy. Although Russell had a long and successful career as an environmental journalist, the materials in the Dick Russell papers focus on his Kennedy assassination research. The content ranges from exclusive interviews and copious notes to collections of speculative articles. The records in the collection are from 1924-2011 with the bulk of the material spanning the years 1959-2011.
The large The Man Who Knew Too Much (TMWKTM) series contains years of extensive research files and drafts for Russell’s popular history of the John F. Kennedy assassination, published in 1992. The research files are arranged alphabetically with the draft manuscripts separated by year from the rest of the series. The small set of files for the Coalition on Political Assassinations includes financial reports and conference information from 1994-1995. Additional JFK Research materials are located under the short JFK Research series; most of this information was compiled in the 1990s or early 2000s, after the publication of TMWKTM.
The bulk of the material is located in the aforementioned TMWKTM series and in the Subject Files series, which is arranged alphabetically and contains research that pertains tangentially to the Kennedy assassination in addition to disparate historical topics ranging from Early American History to Watergate. Most subjects deal with scandal, assassinations, or times of turmoil, usually in the context of government or politics. The last portion of the collection is contained in the Unpublished Book Projects series, which includes drafts of two unfinished book projects entitled “The Assassination Records Review Board” and “Closing In.”
Arrangement
Prior to this finding aid, the papers were arranged topically, similarly to the current arrangement, with only minor rearrangements having taken place for clarity. Currently, the collection is arranged topically in five main series: I. The Man Who Knew Too Much (TMWKTM), II. Coalition on Political Assassinations, III. JFK Research, IV. Subject Files, and V. Unpublished Book Projects.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 101.
Related Resources
Related references
Dick Russell Papers, Accession # 101, Baylor Collections of Political Materials, W. R. Poage Legislative Library, Baylor University.
"Dick Russell." IslandPress. Accessed September 21, 2017.
Russell, Dick. "About the Author." Accessed September 21, 2017.
Simkin, John. "Dick Russell." Spartacus Educational. Accessed September 21, 2017.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Castro, Fidel, 1926-2016.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Assassination.; Russell, Dick--Archives.
Subjects (Organizations)
Coalition on Political Assassinations.
Places
Cuba -- Foreign relations -- United States.; Cuba -- History -- Invasion, 1961.
Subjects
Conspiracy theories.; Political corruption -- United States.; United States -- Foreign Relations -- Cuba.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Manuscripts.; Proofs (Printing); Records (Documents)
- The Man Who Knew Too Much, 1990-2003, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The The Man Who Knew Too Much (TMWKTM) series contains extensive research files and drafts for Russell’s 1992 history of the John F. Kennedy assassination. The research files are arranged alphabetically, with the draft manuscripts separated by year from the rest of the series.
  - Research Files, undated; 1
    - Alpha 66, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agee, Phillip, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Anderson, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Angleton, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arcacha, Sergio, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Artime, Manuel (Interview), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Assassination Bureau D-11 No. 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Assassination Bureau (AIB), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Assassinations - U.S., undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Attwood, William (Interview), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Augustinovich, Ronald (Interview), undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Augustinovich, Ronald D-11 No. 5, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Baker, Bobby, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Barry, Bill D-11 No. 6, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bay of Pigs and Missile Crisis, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Beckham, Thomas, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Belin, David, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bethel, Paul D-11 No. 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bishop, William/O’Have, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bolden, Abraham, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bostick, Deane, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bottos, Alex, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Brading, Eugenett, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bringuier, Carlos, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Brown, Robert K., undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Brown, Robert K. (Interview), undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bush, George, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Cabell, Charles, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Carroll, Paul V., undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Carson, William, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Casey, Marty, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Castro, Fidel - JFK Assassination (1 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Castro, Fidel - JFK Assassination (2 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Castro, Fidel - Plots to Assassinate, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Cohen, Jeff, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Cohn, Roy, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Conein, Lucien, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Congress, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Cressy, M.S. on JFK Assassination, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Crisman, Fred Lee, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Critics, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cuban Exiles (2 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cuban Exiles (1 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Cubela, Rolando, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cutler, Robert (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cutler, Robert (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Dallas Police (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dallas Police (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Davis, Thomas, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - De Mohrenschildt - Anderson, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - De Mohrenschildt, George (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - De Mohrenschildt, George (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Dean, Harry (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Dean, Harry (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Del Valle, Eladio, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Dinkin, Eugene, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Downing, Thomas, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Dulles, Allen, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Ellsworth, Frank, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Exner, Judith Campbell, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - “Farewell America”, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Fensterwald, Bernard, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Fensterwald, Bernard (Interview), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Ferrell, Mary, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Ferrie, David, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Fitzgerald, Desmond, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Fonzi, Gaeton (Interviews, Correspondence), undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - French Connection (1 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - French Connection (2 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - French Connection (3 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Gale, William P., undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Garrison, Jim (1 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Garrison, Jim (2 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Gaudet, William George, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Gayn, Mark (1 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Gayn, Mark (2 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Gehlen, Gen. Reinhard, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Gentry, James (Interviews), undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Giancana, Sam, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Glenn, John, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Golz, Earl, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Gonzalez, Henry, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Hall, Loran (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Hall, Loran (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Hall-Weisbery Interview 412.0, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Hamelson, Charles, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Helms, Richard, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Hemming, Gerry Patrick (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Hemming, Gerry Patrick (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Hicks, James, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Hoch, Paul (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Hoch, Paul (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hoffa, Jimmy (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Hoffa, Jimmy (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Howard, Lawrence, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Howard, Lawrence (Interview), undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Hudkins, Lonnie (Interview), undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Hunts, H.L., undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Hunts, H.L. (Family), undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Hurt, Henry, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Jaworski, Leon, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - JFK, Assassination of, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - JFK Assassination - CIA (1 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - JFK Assassination - CIA (2 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - JFK Assassination - FBI (1 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - JFK Assassination - FBI (2 of 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - JFK Assassination - Military, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B., undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Jones, Penn (Mysterious Deaths), undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Kail, Samuel (Interview), undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Korshak, Sidney, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Korth, Fred, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kroman, David, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Lane, Mark (1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Lane, Mark (2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lansky, Meyer, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Lawrence, Jack, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - LHO - Mexico City, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Maheu, Robert (1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Maheu, Robert (2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Malone, Scott, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Marcello, Carlos, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Marchetti, Victor (Interview), undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Masferrer, Rolando, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Massen, John Thomas, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - McKeown, Robert (Interview), undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - McLaney, Mike, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Mecom, John, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Media - Assassinations, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Media - JFK Assassination, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Merritt, Robert (Watergate), undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Mitteer, J.A., undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Mob - JFK Assassination General, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Molina, Enrique Rivera (Interview), undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Moore, Sara Jane, Assassination Attempt on Ford, 1975, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Morgan, Edward P. (Interview), undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Morrow, Robert D. (1 of 2), undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Morrow, Robert D. (2 of 2), undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Morrow, Robert D. (Interview), undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Murchison, Clint, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Murret, Marilyn, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Norton, Donald P., undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Novel, Gordon, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Novel, Gordon (Interviews), undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Nunez, Emilio, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Occult & Assassinations, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Odio, Sylvia (Interviews), undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Oliver, Revilo, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Oliver Stone Movie, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Osborne, Albert, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Oswald, Lee - Intelligence (1 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Oswald, Lee - Intelligence (2 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Oswald, Lee - Mexico (1 of 2), undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Oswald, Lee - Mexico (2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Oswald, Lee - TV Shows, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Oswald, Marguerite, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Oswald, Marina, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Otepka, Otto, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - O’Toole, George (1 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - O’Toole, George (2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Paine, Ruth, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Paine, Ruth & Michael (Interview), undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Paisley Case - Clips, CIA & FBI Files (1 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Paisley Case — Clips, CIA & FBI Files (2 of 2), undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Paisley Case Depositions (1 of 3), undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Paisley Case Depositions (2 of 3), undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Paisley Case Depositions (3 of 3), undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Paisley, John - Interviews & Gallery M.S. (1 of 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Paisley, John - Interviews & Gallery M.S. (2 of 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Parr, George, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Pawley, William, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Phillips, David, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Popkin, Richard, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Posner Book, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Power, Harry L., undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Prio, Dr. Carlos, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Prouty, Fletcher (Interviews), undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Quiroga, Carlos, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Ray, Manuel (Jure), undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Rifles - JFK Assassination, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Right Wing (General), undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Rodriguez, Manuel O., undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Roselli, John, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Ruby, Jack (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Ruby, Jack (2 of 2), undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Salant, Robert F., undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Schweiker, Richard, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Scott, Peter Dale, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Scott, Peter Dale - JFK/Cuba M.S. (1 of 3), undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Scott, Peter Dale - JFK/Cuba M.S. (2 of 3), undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Scott, Peter Dale - JFK/Cuba M.S. (3 of 3), undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Sinatra, Frank, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Soldiers of Fortune, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Sougtre, Jean - JFK Case, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Soviet Union - JFK Assassination, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Sprague, Richard A., undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Sprague, Richard E. (1 of 2), undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Sprague, Richard E. (2 of 2), undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Sprague, Richard E. - Manuscript (1 of 2), undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Sprague, Richard E. - Manuscript (2 of 2), undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - St. George, Andrew, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - St. George, Andrew (Interviews), undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Sturgis, Frank, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Sturgis, Frank (Interviews), undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Teamsters Union, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - The Third Decade (1 of 2), undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - The Third Decade (2 of 2), undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Thornley, Kerry, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Torbitt Manuscript (1 of 2), undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Torbitt Manuscript (2 of 2), undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Torbitt, MS, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Trafficante, Santo, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Underhill, Gary, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Underhill, Gary (Interviews), undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Veciana, Antonio, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Walsh, Kevin, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Warren Commission, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Werbell, Mitch III, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - White, Roscoe, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - White Russians - LHO - CIA, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Williams, Edward Bennett, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Youngblood, Jack (1 of 2), undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Youngblood, Jack (2 of 2), undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Zapruder Film, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - 1991 Manuscript, 2
    - Carl Oglesby Edits, 1991; 1
      - Preface, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Introduction, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Ch. 1: The Man Who Got Himself Arrested, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Ch. 2: Beginnings, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Ch. 3: First Encounter, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Ch. 4: A Family’s Story: Origins of a Spy, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Ch. 5: Echoes from the Far East, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Ch. 6: Genesis of a Relationship - Nagel and Oswald in Japan, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Ch. 7: Tokyo Triangles, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Ch. 8: California Odyssey, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Ch. 9-10: The CIA, The KGB, and Oswald in the USSR, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Ch. 11: Double Game in Mexico, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Ch. 12: The First Plot to Kill JFK, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Ch. 13: Oswald and the Baron, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Ch. 14: Conjunction of Forces, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Ch. 15: The Secret War Over Cuba, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Ch. 16: The Second Plot to Kill JFK, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Ch. 18: Mysteries of Mexico City, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Ch. 19: Oswald Recruited, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Ch. 20: The Third Plot to Kill JFK, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Ch. 21: Orders from the KGB Eliminate Oswald, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Ch. 22: The Colonel, The Cuban Exiles, and The Mob, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Ch. 23: Oswald’s Strange September Voyage, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Ch. 24: Countdown to Dallas, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Ch. 25: Patriot Games, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Ch. 26: The Men Behind the Guns, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Ch. 27: The Pentagon, The CIA, and The French Connection, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Ch. 28: Government Cover Up, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Ch. 29: The Railroading of Richard Case Nagell, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Ch. 30: Disappearance Behind the Iron Curtain, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Drafts, 1991; 2
      - Introduction: The Most Important Witness Now Living, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Preface: Man in the Middle: Richard Case Nagell and the Assassination of John. F. Kennedy, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Ch. 1: Incident in El Paso, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - Ch. 2: Cover up by the FBI, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - Ch. 3: Prelude to Trial, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Ch. 4: The First Trial of Richard Case Nagell, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Ch. 5: Aftermath and Prison, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - 1992 Manuscript, 3
    - Book Proposal Package, 1992; 1
      - Book Proposal Package, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Chapter Outlines, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Chapter 1, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Chapter 2, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Chapter 3, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Chapter 4, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Chapter 5, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Chapter 6, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Chapter 7, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Chapter 8, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Chapter 9, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Chapter 10, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Chapter 11, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Chapter 12, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Chapter 13, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - Chapter 14, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Chapter 15, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Chapter 16, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Chapter 17, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - Chapter 18, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - Chapter 19, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Chapter 20, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - Chapter 21, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - Chapter 22, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 21)